[
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 255,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 255,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Marsor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A plump merchant",
            "job": "I sell wine!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "WINE",
            "keyword2": "VINT",
            "answer1": "I have some good vintages.",
            "answer2": "I own my own vineyards, they are on an isle northeast of here!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou like wine?",
            "yesanswer": "Ah, then join me in a glass!",
            "noanswer": "Don't know what thou art missing!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 203,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Green Beard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall pirate with a green beard!",
            "job": "I'm buying armour for my crew!",
            "heal": "Jolly good mate!",
            "keyword1": "ARMO",
            "keyword2": "NOWH",
            "answer1": "I hope to get some magical plate!",
            "answer2": "Oh, I see.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know where to buy mystic armour?",
            "yesanswer": "Where?",
            "noanswer": "Wish I did!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 225,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Ignap",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A towering wizard.",
            "job": "I must warn thee!",
            "heal": "Adequate.",
            "keyword1": "WARN",
            "keyword2": "DOOM",
            "answer1": "To step into those woods will seal thy doom!",
            "answer2": "In there lies the dark side, enter not!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Shalt thou go on?",
            "yesanswer": "Evil shall consume thee!",
            "noanswer": "Wise decision!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 194,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Boris",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "An ugly orc!",
            "job": "I smuggle black market items.",
            "heal": "Good'n smelly.",
            "keyword1": "ITEM",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "Magic keys, magic gems, that sort of thing.",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou need such an item?",
            "yesanswer": "I just gave the guild shop a new supply!",
            "noanswer": "Ah well, maybe next time."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 164,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 128,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Brigant",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A big fat troll.",
            "job": "Aw, buzz off!",
            "heal": "Shove it!",
            "keyword1": "IT  ",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "Thy face!",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Did thou hear me?",
            "yesanswer": "Then do it!",
            "noanswer": "I said shove it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 226,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Starlight",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mage dressed all in black.",
            "job": "I use black magic!",
            "heal": "Dark indeed.",
            "keyword1": "MAGI",
            "keyword2": "MIX ",
            "answer1": "I cast powerful magic missile spells.",
            "answer2": "Try one black pearl and one part sulfurous ash!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou should try my mix of reagents!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 136,
        "x_pos1": 30,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 255,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 137,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 255,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 136,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 255,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 203,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jeremy James Scirlock",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A sneaky thief!",
            "job": "At thy service!",
            "heal": "Very well!",
            "keyword1": "SERV",
            "keyword2": "HYTH",
            "answer1": "How about information?",
            "answer2": "The dungeon Hythloth can only be reached by a secret entrance in the great castle.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek a special dungeon?",
            "yesanswer": "Which?",
            "noanswer": "I cannot help thee."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Seanna",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A slinky mage.",
            "job": "I am a sorceress",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "MAGI",
            "keyword2": "SLEE",
            "answer1": "How about the sleep spell... sleep... sleep....",
            "answer2": "A sleep spell requires but one part silk! sleep... sleep... sleep...",
            "yesnoquestion": "My dear friend, may I help you?",
            "yesanswer": "How about with thy magic?",
            "noanswer": "Ah"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 202,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 16,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Slysam",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A nimble thief.",
            "job": "What's it to thee?",
            "heal": "As good as I need be!",
            "keyword1": "THIE",
            "keyword2": "CLEV",
            "answer1": "Yea, and clever too.",
            "answer2": "Thou dost ask too many questions!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou a thief?",
            "yesanswer": "Oh, I'd better watch out!",
            "noanswer": "Just as I thought"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 200,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sailor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A scruffy sailor",
            "job": "I am a sailor!",
            "heal": "Salty.",
            "keyword1": "SAIL",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "Oh, a sailor's life is the life for me,",
            "answer2": "As I sail across the bounding sea!",
            "yesnoquestion": "The rest?",
            "yesanswer": "And never ever ever do I worry 'bout the weather, for the weather never ever did a thing for me!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sniflet",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A cowering man.",
            "job": "I am hiding.",
            "heal": "O.K. for now.",
            "keyword1": "HIDE",
            "keyword2": "SOME",
            "answer1": "I know something others want!",
            "answer2": "I... I...",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou promise to use it only to aid the powers of good?",
            "yesanswer": "The lighter than air device that was stolen lies near the dungeon Hythloth!",
            "noanswer": "Oh, no."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 203,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sailor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A scruffy sailor",
            "job": "I am a sailor!",
            "heal": "Salty.",
            "keyword1": "SAIL",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "Oh, a sailor's life is the life for me,",
            "answer2": "As I sail across the bounding sea!",
            "yesnoquestion": "The rest?",
            "yesanswer": "And never ever ever do I worry 'bout the weather, for the weather never ever did a thing for me!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 40,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dancek",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A jolly old soul.",
            "job": "I am a tinker by trade.",
            "heal": "Jolly good, thanks.",
            "keyword1": "TINK",
            "keyword2": "MACH",
            "answer1": "I create projectile machinery.",
            "answer2": "Primarily ship cannons!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou own a ship!",
            "yesanswer": "Good odds I built the cannons!",
            "noanswer": "Thou really should get one!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 202,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sailor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A scruffy sailor",
            "job": "I am a sailor!",
            "heal": "Salty.",
            "keyword1": "SAIL",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "Oh, a sailor's life is the life for me,",
            "answer2": "As I sail across the bounding sea!",
            "yesnoquestion": "The rest?",
            "yesanswer": "And never ever ever do I worry 'bout the weather, for the weather never ever did a thing for me!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 200,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sailor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A scruffy sailor",
            "job": "I am a sailor!",
            "heal": "Salty.",
            "keyword1": "SAIL",
            "keyword2": "LIFE",
            "answer1": "Oh, a sailor's life is the life for me,",
            "answer2": "As I sail across the bounding sea!",
            "yesnoquestion": "The rest?",
            "yesanswer": "And never ever ever do I worry 'bout the weather, for the weather never ever did a thing for me!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 203,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Silver John",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall sailor.",
            "job": "I'm a pirate matey!",
            "heal": "Good enough, eh!",
            "keyword1": "PIRA",
            "keyword2": "RAID",
            "answer1": "We raid the coasts of Britannia, fun eh!",
            "answer2": "Pillage and burn!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou a pirate?",
            "yesanswer": "Good matey!",
            "noanswer": "Thou had best leave this place 'fore there's any trouble!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Rankbreath",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall, muscular, impressive guard.",
            "job": "I am a guard.",
            "heal": "Very hungry!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "HUNG",
            "answer1": "I guard the city!",
            "answer2": "Yes, I am very hungry!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou here to feed me?",
            "yesanswer": "I am grateful.",
            "noanswer": "Then thou had better run!!!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Rankbreath",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall, muscular, impressive guard.",
            "job": "I am a guard.",
            "heal": "Very hungry!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "HUNG",
            "answer1": "I guard the city!",
            "answer2": "Yes, I am very hungry!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou here to feed me?",
            "yesanswer": "I am grateful.",
            "noanswer": "Then thou had better run!!!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Rankbreath",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall, muscular, impressive guard.",
            "job": "I am a guard.",
            "heal": "Very hungry!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "HUNG",
            "answer1": "I guard the city!",
            "answer2": "Yes, I am very hungry!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou here to feed me?",
            "yesanswer": "I am grateful.",
            "noanswer": "Then thou had better run!!!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 44,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 16,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Ragnar",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A solemn ranger",
            "job": "I travel.",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "TRAV",
            "keyword2": "SKUL",
            "answer1": "The lands of Britannia.",
            "answer2": "Be warned that if thou dost ever use the skull, except to destroy it, all thy virtues will be lost!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou here looking for information?",
            "yesanswer": "On what?",
            "noanswer": "Then buzz off."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Roofus",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mean looking guard.",
            "job": "We guard the bridge slime!",
            "heal": "What's it to ya scumpuppy!",
            "keyword1": "BRID",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "This bridge ya stupid jerk!",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou a wise &##!?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou had best ditch it then!",
            "noanswer": "Then just buzz off!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Roofus",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mean looking guard.",
            "job": "We guard the bridge slime!",
            "heal": "What's it to ya scumpuppy!",
            "keyword1": "BRID",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "This bridge ya stupid jerk!",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou a wise &##!?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou had best ditch it then!",
            "noanswer": "Then just buzz off!"
        }
    }
]